[ 
    {
        "question": "What year did the first Godzilla film, Gojira, release in Japan?",
        "answers": [
            "1960",
            "1954",
            "1956",
            "1945"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "1954",
        "explanation": "Gojira, Godzilla's first film, released in October 1954, Less than a decade after World War II."
    },
    {
        "question": "What monster was Godzilla's first opponent?",
        "answers": [
            "King Kong",
            "Mothra",
            "Anguirus",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Anguirus",
        "explanation": "In Godzilla Raids Again (1956), the King of the Monsters would face his first opponent, the ferocious Anguirus!"
    },
    {
        "question": "True or False: Godzilla's original japanese name is also Godzilla.",
        "answers": [
            "True",
            "False"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "False",
        "explanation": "Godzilla is actually the westernized version of the monsters original name, Gojira. A name that is a combination of the japanese words for gorilla and whale."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these Godzilla monsters are aliens?",
        "answers": [
            "King Ghidorah",
            "Mothra",
            "Rodan",
            "Baragon"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "King Ghidorah",
        "explanation": "In Ghidorah, The Three Headed Monster (1964), the triple-head beast is described to be an alien from Venus."
    },
    {
        "question": "True or False: In King Kong Vs Godzilla, King Kong is the victor.",
        "answers": [
            "True",
            "False"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "True",
        "explanation": "Despite popular misconception, it's actually Kong that's the winner of the fight between him and Godzilla."
    },
    {
        "question": "What year did Godzilla made his first appearance in a color film?",
        "answers": [
            "1965",
            "1954",
            "1985",
            "1962"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "1962",
        "explanation": "Godzilla's first appearance in color would actually be in 1962, in King Kong Vs Godzilla!"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these movies did Godzilla battle a giant plant monster?",
        "answers": [
            "Godzilla Vs Biollante",
            "Return of Godzilla",
            "Mothra Vs Godzilla",
            "Godzilla Vs King Ghidorah"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Godzilla Vs Biollante",
        "explanation": "Biollante is a giant monster that is created by combining the DNA of Godzilla, a plant, and a human child, making it one of the G-man's most unique opponents."
    },
    {
        "question": "In the Marvel Godzilla comics published in the 1970s, it is stated that the giant monster's strength is equal to which of these Avengers?",
        "answers": [
            "Iron Man",
            "Thor",
            "Hulk",
            "Captain Marvel"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Thor",
        "explanation": "In a battle between Godzilla and the Avengers, it's revealed to the readers that the monster matches in strength with the God of Thunder, Thor!"
    },
    {
        "question": "True or False: Godzilla has never been killed in any of the movies.",
        "answers": [
            "True",
            "False"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "False",
        "explanation": "Despite being one of the most powerful fictional creatures in cinema, Godzilla has actually been killed at least 5 times in the entire franchise, 6 if you include the American Godzilla from 1998."
    },
    {
        "question": "Godzilla is the King of the Monsters",
        "answers": [
            "True",
            "True",
            "True",
            "True"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "True",
        "explanation": "Godzilla was, is, and always will be, the KING OF THE MONSTERS!"
    }
]